Lose your heart and come to your senses.
Sense and Sensibility is a drama, romance film directed by Ang Lee.
The Dashwood sisters, sensible Elinor and passionate Marianne, learn that their
prospects of marriage seem doomed by their family's sudden loss of fortune.
After Henry Dashwood dies unexpectedly, his estate
must pass on by law to his son.
These circumstances leave Mr.
Dashwood's wife and daughters without a home and
with barely enough money to live on.
As Elinor and Marianne struggle to find romantic fulfillment in a society obsessed with financial and social
status, they must learn to mix sense with sensibility in their dealings with both money and men.
Elinor Dashwood, played by Emma Thompson.
Marianne Dashwood, played by Kate Winslet.
Colonel Christopher Brandon, played by Alan Rickman.
Edward Ferrars, played by Hugh Grant.
Mrs. Dashwood, played by Gemma Jones.
John Willoughby, played by Greg Wise.
Sense and Sensibility is a 1995 period drama film directed by Ang Lee
and based on Jane Austen's 1811 novel of the same name.
Emma Thompson wrote the screenplay and stars as Elinor Dashwood, while
Kate Winslet plays Elinor's younger sister Marianne.
The story follows the Dashwood sisters, members of a wealthy English family of landed
gentry, as they must deal with circumstances of sudden destitution.
They are forced to seek financial security through marriage.
Hugh Grant and Alan Rickman play their respective suitors.
Producer Lindsay Doran, a long time admirer of Austen's
novel, hired Thompson to write the screenplay.
She spent five years drafting numerous revisions, continually working on the script
between other films as well as into production of the film itself.
Studios were nervous that Thompson—a first-time screenwriter—was the credited
writer, but Columbia Pictures agreed to distribute the film.
Though initially intending to have another actress portray
Elinor, Thompson was persuaded to take the role.
Thompson's screenplay exaggerated the Dashwood family's wealth to make their
later scenes of poverty more apparent to modern audiences.
It also altered the traits of the male leads to make them
more appealing to contemporary viewers.
Elinor and Marianne's different characteristics were
emphasised through imagery and invented scenes.
Lee was selected as director, both for his work in the 1993 film The Wedding Banquet and
because Doran believed he would help the film appeal to a wider audience.
Lee was given a budget of $16 million.
Sense and Sensibility was released on 13 December 1995, in the United States.
A commercial success, earning $135 million worldwide, the film garnered overwhelmingly positive reviews upon release and
received many accolades, including three awards and eleven nominations at the 1995 British Academy Film Awards.
It earned seven Academy Awards nominations, including
for Best Picture and Best Actress.
Thompson received the award for Best Adapted Screenplay, becoming the only
person to have won Academy Awards for both acting and screenwriting.
Sense and Sensibility contributed to a resurgence in popularity for Austen's
works, and has led to many more productions in similar genres.
It continues to be recognised as one of the best Austen adaptations of all time.
The film explores themes of secret love, london, england,
countryside, based on novel or book, widow.
The tone is emotional.